A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, Stack Material, RG 2 FA246
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, general correspondence, Stack Material, RG 2
1959-1979
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA246
5.62 Cubic Feet 13 letter document boxes, 1 half-letter document box, and 1 oversize box
Scope and Contents
The stack material serves as a supplement to the General Correspondence, and the existence of these records are often noted within the applicable general correspondence file.
Conditions Governing Access
Records ten years old and older are open for research.
- General Correspondence, 1958; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - United States, 1958; 1958/200
    - University of California - Institute of International Studies, Berkley - Mimeographed Statements Mentioned in Paul Taylor's Letter to NSB, 1958 January 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence, 1959; 1.63 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes and 1 oversize box
  - United States, 1959; 1959/200
    - Slavic Studies Joint Committee - "an appraisal of Russian Studies in the U.S." - "Russian and Other Non-Western areas in Undergraduate Education", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - JHU - School of Advanced International Studies Southeast Asia Program - A Chronology of Burma's International Relations 1945-1959 - A publication of the Rangoon-Hopkins for Southeast Asian Studies - Rangoon University, Rangoon, Burma (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Latin America, 1959; 1959/300
    - McK-1 - Diary of Trip to Chile by Erskine McKinley, May 30 - June 3, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - McK-2 - Diary of Trip to Brazil, Argentina, Chile, and Colombia by Erskine McKinley, November 12 - December 2, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brazil, 1959; 1959/305
    - Governo Carvalho Pinto - "The 5 year plan of the Governor of the State of Sao Paolo" - 9/24/59, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - University of Panama - "American Society of Human Genetics", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - University of Rio Grande - "Salzano", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - University of Sao Paolo - "Saldanha", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - University of Sao Paolo - "Radioisotope lab, Primeiro Curso de Medicina nuclear - 25 de Janeiroa 17 de Marco de 1959. Centro de medicina nuclear Faculdade de Medicina Da Universidad de Sao Paolo" (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 15, Folder 117)
    - University of Sao Paolo - "Frota-Pessoa, O.", 1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Canada, 1959; 1959/427
    - Atomic Energy of Canada - "Human Hereditary", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - South Asia Region, 1959; 1959/460
    - Gil-4 - "Chadbourne Gilpatrick, Asia Trip", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gil-4 - "Interviews, Chadbourne Gilpatrick, South Asia Trip", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Africa, 1959; 1959/475
    - July-2 - "Robert W. July's Diary - Africa, Belgium, England, and France - February 2 - April 25, 1959" (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Asia, 1959; 1959/600
    - Evans-6 - "Roger F. Evans, Asia Trip 1959, January 21st - February 27th Japan + Philippines" (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Europe, 1959; 1959/700
    - Mck-4 - "Diary of Trip to Japan, Austria, England, Holland, and Belgium. By Erskine W. McKinley February 9th - March 9th 1959" (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Near East Region, 1959; 1959/804
    - Tho-1 - "Visit to Lebanon, Turkey, and England - KWT - April 9-19, 1959" (Box 3, Folder 18)
- General Correspondence, 1960; 2.01 Cubic Feet 4 letter document boxes and 1 oversize box
  - United States, 1960; 1960/200
    - Gropius, W. - "Architettura Cantiere", 1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Gropius, W. - "Casabella Continuita, August 1960" (Box 3, Folder 20, Box 15, Folder 109)
    - "Massachusetts General Hospital, Crockett, 2/11/60", 1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Stern Family Fund Recognition of Excellence - "The Recognition of Excellence. A staff paper prepared for the Edgar Stern Family Fund, September 1959", 1960 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - City College, Metropolitan Area Study - "New York's Grand Opera War: 1906-1910 - Adolph S. Tomars, January 6th, 1960" (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - National Defense Education Act - "Language Development, 1960" (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - National Defense Education Act - "Language Development: Participants in Conference on Exciting Resources for the Development of Languages and Area Studies for South Asia", 1960 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - NDEA - "Language Development: A Summary and Analysis of the Act Prepared by the Staff of the Committee on Labor and Public Welfare", 1960 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - University of Michigan Political Science - "Basic Theoretical Concepts about International Law: A Framework of Policy and Oriented Inquiry. Myers S. McDougal - Yale University, June 28, 1960" (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - University of Michigan Political Science - "Communist Ideology and International Affairs - Zbigniew Porezeznski, Harvard University. June 28th, 1960" (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - University of Michigan - "Symposium on the Place of Theory in the Conduct and Study of International Relations, Kenneth W. Thompson - June 28th, 1960" (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - SSRC - Political Behavior I - "Papers prepared for Conference on the Comparative Role of Groups in Political Systems. Gould House, Dobbs Ferry, NY. September 12-16th, 1960" (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - SSRC - Political Behavior II - "Papers prepared for Conference on the Comparative Role of Groups in Political Systems. Gould House, Dobbs Ferry, NY. September 12-16th, 1960", 1960 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - SSRC - Political Behavior III - "Papers prepared for Conference on the Comparative Role of Groups in Political Systems. Gould House, Dobbs Ferry, NY. September 12-16th, 1960", 1960 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Latin America, 1960; 1960/300
    - Tho-1 - "Diary of Trip to Latin America by Kenneth Winifred Thompson July 25th-August 12th, 1960" (Box 5, Folder 33)